https://www.appstate.edu/privacy/

Skip to main content
Information For...
Home
The university remains open, with emergency management protocols activated
and operational modifications and precautions in place. Read the latest updates
Appalachian Privacy Statement
Last Revised: Feb. 7, 2020
Appalachian State University (“Appalachian”) is dedicated to protecting the privacy of our Appalachian community and visitors. The purpose of this Privacy Statement (the “Statement”) is to inform you of our privacy practices, the information we collect from you and how we process your data.
This Statement applies to Appalachian’s website www.appstate.edu and the network of websites Appalachian owns and controls (collectively, “Appalachian Sites”).
This Statement does not apply to employment-related or personal information, collected in the scope of employment or in connection to duties performed on behalf of Appalachian, from or about current or former employees, contractors, volunteers, post-doctorate fellows, and other related Appalachian representatives.
Some Appalachian Sites may have specific privacy statements concerning the collection and use of your personal data. Where applicable, all Appalachian faculty and staff contributing to Appalachian Sites are requested to post more specific privacy statements relevant to the collection and use of personal information associated with those sites. Those specific privacy statements should be approved by University Communications prior to their publication.
Collection of Personal Information
Information you share:
Appalachian may collect any personal information you directly and voluntarily share with us through Appalachian online platforms, such as email portals, online forms, and electronic surveys. This personal information may include your name and contact information, purchasing information (e.g., credit card information), or social security number. By providing this personal information you acknowledge that, where permitted by federal or state law, Appalachian may use this information for the express purposes for which the information was provided, administrative purposes, as well as to improve services and online content provided by Appalachian.
Information we collect:
When you visit Appalachian Sites, we automatically collect information from you using website tracking technology, including but not limited to Google Analytics.
The information gathered includes the Appalachian Sites you visit, the date and length of time of each visit, websites visited before or after visiting our sites, the browser and IP address used to access our sites, details of the visits including search queries conducted, and other related information.
Additionally, Appalachian collects information from you through the use of cookies. Cookies are small files that are stored on your computer, and are used to assist us personalize your online experience by saving your preferences for future visits and improving services and online content.
By visiting Appalachian Sites, you acknowledge that, where permitted by federal or state law, Appalachian may collect this information to assist, manage and improve online content to deliver the best user experience; provide, customize and personalize communications and market our activities to you; as well as to protect Appalachian networks from unauthorized or harmful activities, such as network system security breaches and other harmful threats.
Other Privacy Practices
Personal Information of Children
Unless otherwise provided, Appalachian Sites are not intended or designed for children under the age of 13. Additionally, Appalachian does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from children under the age of 13.
In limited instances where an Appalachian website does collect personal information from children online, Appalachian will make reasonable efforts to ensure that a parent or guardian of the child receives notice of Appalachian privacy practices concerning their child’s personal information. Furthermore, those websites will have privacy statements notifying parents of privacy practices concerning personal information collected and other related privacy practices.
Appalachian faculty and staff that maintain Appalachian Sites are required to notify University Communications of any websites they maintain that are intended and designed for children.
Sharing information with Third Parties
Appalachian works with many vendors and other partners who assist us with our daily operations. Information we have acquired, as expressed above, will only be shared with these third parties to perform services on behalf of Appalachian. Third party organizations may not use the information we provide them for any purpose other than those reasons expressly permitted in contractual agreements with Appalachian, as expressed in this Statement, or as otherwise required by law.
Non-Appalachian Sites
This Statement applies solely to information collected on Appalachian Sites. Appalachian Sites may contain hyperlinks or other website references that direct you to third party websites that are not owned or controlled by Appalachian. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of those third-party websites, including independent websites of faculty, staff, or students that are not owned and controlled by Appalachian.
Personal Information Protection
Consistent with applicable privacy and data security laws, Appalachian has developed, implements, and maintains administrative, technical and physical security measures to preserve the confidentiality and integrity of personal information we receive. This information is safeguarded to prevent unauthorized personnel and other parties from accessing, using, or modifying your personal information. Despite our best efforts to prevent unauthorized access, no security measure is impenetrable and Appalachian does not guarantee that these safeguards will protect your personal information.
Mandatory Disclosure Requirements
Appalachian, as an agency of the State of North Carolina, is required to comply with North Carolina public record laws, as well as other state and federal record disclosure requirements.
All records, including email, Appalachian receives in connection with the transaction of university business are subject to public disclosure, unless a legal basis requires maintaining the confidentiality of the record. Even in instances when a record is subject to confidentiality, Appalachian may be required to disclose this information to comply with state and federal law.
Retention of Personal Information
Appalachian retention practices are subject to the requirements of state and federal law, as well as institutional policies. For more information on our retention practices, please visit Appalachian Records Management.
International Data Subject Rights
If you are present in a European Economic Area (EEA) or any country that is subject to the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), then you may be entitled to certain rights pertaining to the processing of personal information collected from you during your time in that country. If so, the processing of your personal information will be conducted pursuant to a lawful basis as prescribed in the GDPR, including but not limited to consent, necessity for contractual performance, necessity of a legitimate interest, or legal compliance.
Under the GDPR, you may have the following rights regarding the processing of your personal information:
Right to confirm whether Appalachian processes your personal information;
Right to request access to your personal information, including the purpose for processing, the categories of personal data processed, information about third parties with whom Appalachian may disclose your personal information, and the retention period for your personal information;
Right to transfer your personal information;
Right to restrict how Appalachian processes your personal information;
Right to request correction of your personal information that is incomplete or inaccurate;
Right to request deletion of your personal information in limited circumstances;
Right to object to the collection, processing, retention or use of your personal information;
Right to withdraw consent to the processing of personal information in matters where processing was based on consent;
Right not be subject to decisions based solely on automated processing including profiling; and
Right to file a complaint with appropriate supervisory authorities, including countries in the EEA or other countries subject to the GDPR.
If you choose to exercise these rights, Appalachian may be unable to effectively offer you university services. Additionally, we may be required to deny your requests to meet state and federal legal obligations. For more information on the GDPR and your rights, please visit Appalachians GDPR Privacy Notice.
Legal Compliance
Appalachian complies with applicable federal and state laws, as well as UNC System and Appalachian policies, for the collection, use, and disclosure of personal information. When permitted by applicable law, Appalachian may disclose personal information to third parties when compelled by law or to protect the safety and security of the Appalachian community or property.
Updates to Privacy Statement
This Privacy Statement may be amended at any time without notice. Appalachian encourages you to review this website periodically to ensure you have read the most updated statement. Appalachian, when required by law, will notify you of any changes.
Questions and Concerns
If you have any questions or concerns about the collection and processing of your personal data, please send an email to privacy@appstate.edu.
Apply
Visit
Connect
Degrees
